Finding Aid for the Adelbert Bartlett Papers LSC.1300
UCLA Library Special Collections
Adelbert Bartlett papers
1922-1950
UCLA Library Special Collections
Bartlett, Adelbert
Abbud, Karimeh, 1896-1955
LSC.1300
24.0 linear feet (48 boxes and 21 oversize boxes)
Adelbert Bartlett was a commercial photographer based in Santa Monica, California, and the director of the Near East Relief Fund in Los Angeles. The collection contains photographs, negatives, periodicals, scrapbooks, and memorabilia relating to Bartlett's life as a commercial photographer and to his involvement with the Near East Relief Fund.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Carolyn Bartlett Farnham, 1981-85.
Gift of Richards K. Farnham, 1985-86.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942303593606533
Biography
Adelbert Bartlett was born in 1887; became a commercial photographer based in Santa Monica, California; his photographs of the Southern California lifestyle were widely published in the U.S. and abroad; director, Near East Relief Fund regional headquarters news bureau in Los Angeles; worked for the Fund in Greece, Palestine, and Syria; died in 1966.
Scope and Content
Collection contains photographs, negatives, periodicals, scrapbooks, and memorabilia relating to Bartlett's life as a commercial photographer and to his involvement with the Near East Relief Fund.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Photographs of the Near East.
Photographs of California and the U.S.
Photographs of Europe.
Ephemera and memorabilia.
Online Items Available
Portions of this collection have been digitized and are available online: Adelbert Bartlett Papers (2629 items).
Photographs.; Commercial photography -- Specimens.; Photographers -- California, Southern -- Archives.; Bartlett, Adelbert, 1887-1966--Archives.; Near East Relief (Organization)
- Bartlett
  - Carolyn Bartlett
    - Interior Designs (school work) (Box 68, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence
    - With U.S. Govt. - Strategic Services, Pictorial Records Section (Box 65, Folder 14)
    - General (Box 65, Folder 15)
    - Re: Dr. David Wharton James, Edward Vischer and CC Pierce (Box 65, Folder 16)
    - Postcards received (Box 65, Folder 17)
  - Personal
    - Family, negatives (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Photographs of Carolyn Bartlett Farnham (Box 65, Folder 8)
    - One of Dick Farnham's forebears (Box 65, Folder 9)
    - Photos of AB (?) (Box 65, Folder 11)
    - Travel background (Box 66, Folder 5)
    - Art work by Carolyn Bartlett Farnham, AB & others (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - Exhibit Signage (Box 68, Folder 4)
- Clippings
  - Clippings relating to negatives and prints., 4 leaves (Box 10, Folder 2)
    Scope and Contents note
    [See Box 30]
- Embroidery from Asia Minor
  - Linen runner, (112 cm. x 43 cm.) embroidered with multi-colored butterflies. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Bride's head shawl, (Turkish, 113 cm. x 58 cm.). (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Red, blue and gold embroidery on linen, with nine figures.
  - Blouse, (sheer fabric). Multi-colored embroidery on collar, sleeves and waistband. (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Ephemera
  - Barlett, Adelbert., 16 items (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Near East., 10 items, 12 leaves (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Near East. Education., 8 items. 9 leaves (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Near East. Greece., 6 items. 7 leaves (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Near East. Palestine., 25 items. 42 leaves (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Near East. Turkey., 11 items. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Near East Relief. Advertising copy., 1 item. 78 leaves (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Near East Relief. International Golden Rule Sunday., 1 book. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Near East Relief. International Golden Rule Sunday., 11 items. 25 leaves (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Near East Relief. Miscellaneous ephemera., 31 items. 67 leaves (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Near East Relief. Outline of Milk Campaign., 1 item. 20 leaves (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Near East Relief. Publicity materialeaves, 21 items. 35 leaves (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Religious education of children under Near East Relief care., 1 item. 21 leaves (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Non-Near East Ephemera. Murals of the Los Angeles Public Library., 2 items. 3 leaves (Box 2, Folder 14)
    General note
    (See Box 1, f.15 for photographs)
- Foreign
  - Miscellaneous (Box 22, Folder 24)
- Glass negatives
  - Northern California., 9 negatives (Box 20)
  - Bartlett Family., 6 negatives. (Box 20)
  - Idaho., 1908 - 1909; 4 negatives. (Box 20)
  - King and Queen of Greece., 1924; 1 negative. (Box 20)
  - Washington State., 1906 - 1912; 17 negatives. (Box 20)
  - Yukon and Alaska., 19 negatives (Box 20)
  - Southern California., 1920s; 12 negatives. (Box 20)
  - Clara & Carolyn Bartlett., 1923; 2 negatives. (Box 20)
  - Clara Bartlett., 1924; 2 negatives. (Box 20)
  - Carolyn Bartlett., undated; 4 negatives (Box 20)
    (Includes zinc half-tone plate)
  - Near East artifacts., 10 negatives (Box 20)
  - Jackie Coogan., 9 negatives (Box 20)
  - Near East Relief Campaign., 5 negatives (Box 20)
  - Near East Relief Organizers., 10 negatives (Box 20)
  - Adelbert Bartlett., undated; 3 negatives (Box 20)
  - Various., 21 negatives. (Box 29)
  - Northern California., 3 negatives (Box 29)
- History
  - Picture Lists - U.S & Foreign - Entire Lists (Box 55, Folder 5)
- Human Interest
  - People (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Objects (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Things, negatives (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - People, negatives (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Children's Home Society (Box 23, Folder 6)
    Including Frank Capra, Basil Rathbone, Mary Pickford, Leo Carillo, Governor Frank Merriam, Bob Hope
  - Children's Home Society - miscellaneous (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Children, [2 folders.] (Box 44, Folder 2-3)
  - Cornshocks (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Nobody's Children - portraits, [2 folders.] (Box 44, Folder 5-6)
  - Easter lillies (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Children's photographs, [2 folders.] (Box 44, Folder 8-9)
  - Movie stars (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Children's Home Society - portraits & others (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Children's Home Society - portraits, [5 folders.] (Box 45, Folder 2-6)
  - Children, [3 folders.] (Box 46, Folder 1-3)
  - People, [3 folders.] (Box 46, Folder 4-6)
  - Lake Arrowhead and California (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Portraits (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Veterans (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Things and animals (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - People (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - Things (Box 66, Folder 2)
  - Color transparencies - paintings (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - Color transparencies - Unidentified (Box 67, Folder 2)
  - Color transparencies - flowers (Box 67, Folder 3)
- Indexes
  - Negative #1 - 2256 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Catalogs of pictures for various series (Box 41, Folder 2)
- Maps
  - Cloth mounted wall map, (105 cms. x 141 cms.). (Box 6, Folder 3)
    Showing areas served by the Near East Relief. Mounted publicity samples from 1922 and 1933 on verso.
  - Wall map of the war in Greece. (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Miscellaneous
  - Unidentified locations (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Album (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Colleges (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Russian costumes (Box 48, Folder 15)
  - Unidentified photos, (4" x 5") [6 folders.] (Box 50, Folder 17-22)
  - Unidentified photographs, (8" x 10") (Box 52, Folder 20)
  - Unidentified photographs - places, (5" x 7") (Box 52, Folder 52)
  - Unidentified auditorium (Box 63, Folder 14)
- Miscellaneous photos
  - People, flowers, (8" x 10") (Box 52, Folder 48)
- Negatives
  - #100 - 831. (Box 24)
    (see also box 10)
  - #833 - 1600. (Box 25)
  - #1601 - 2411. (Box 26)
  - Unnumbered (Box 27)
  - #2412 - 2540. (Box 27)
  - Unnumbered, [2 boxes.] (Box 28, Box 29)
  - "New Series" (Box 29)
    (Santa Monica, Redondo and Washington State)
  - "Palestine etc." from the "Abbott X series", 1925 (Box 29)
  - Lake Le Paige (Box 29)
  - People - miscellaneous (Box 32)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 34)
- Newspaper clippings
  - AB published photos, 1930s and undated; (oversize) (Box 59)
    Published in Houston Chronicle, Hollywood Daily Citizen, Long Beach Press Telegram, San Francisco Chronicle
  - AB published photos, 1920s; (oversize) (Box 60, Folder 1)
    Los Angeles Sunday Magazine, Los Angeles Sunday Times, Long Beach Press Telegram, Los Angeles Evening Herald, Los Angeles Examiner, Sunday Morning Outlook, San Pedro News-Pilot
  - AB published photos, 1920s; (oversize) (Box 60, Folder 2)
    New York Times, San Francisco Chronicle, Detroit News, Minneapolis Journal, Houston Chronicle, Vanderbilt Pictorial
  - Photos of newspaper article by AB (Box 63, Folder 12)
- Notes
  - Notes relating to negatives and prints, 81 leaves (Box 10, Folder 1)
    [See box 30]
- Periodicals
  - "The New Near East". v. 10 no. 6, v. 10 no. 7, December 1925 and March 1926. (Box 12, Folder 1)
    2 items
  - "Outlook West" section of the Evening Outlook, Saturday, April 26, 1980.; 1 item (Box 12, Folder 2)
    (Santa Monica).
  - "The Mentor". v. 15 no. 4, Serial no. 291, May 1927 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    (Contains photographs of the Miramar Hotel in Santa Monica by Adelbert Bartlett on pp. 23-32.) 1 item.
  - "Touring Topics". v. 21 no. 7., July 1929 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    (Contains article, "A Californian in the Holy Land" and photographs by Adelbert Bartlett on pp. 36-41, 45.) 1 item.
  - "California Arts and Architecture". v. 38 no. 1., July 1930 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    (Contains article, "Westwood Village" and photographs by Adelbert Bartlett on pp. 40-45.) 1 item.
  - Extra copies of captions for proof books. (Box 12, Folder 7)
    1800 subjects
  - "Pictorial California". v. 31 no. 2., Spring 1956; 2 items. (Box 12, Folder 3)
    (contains a photograph by Adelbert bartlett on pp. 16-17.)
- Photo Albums
  - Proof photographs of the Middle East, 869 items. (Box 8)
    Including views of Jerusalem, Sidon, Beirut and Cairo.
  - Proof photographs of Europe and the Middle East, 857 items. (Box 9)
    Including views of Greece, France, Italy and Palestine.
  - Proofs of photographs of Palm Springs and other [parts of] CA, 1898-1937; (oversize) (Box 61, Folder 1)
    Includes list of photographs
  - United States - California - Palm Springs, 1935-1937; (oversize) (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - United States - California - Long Beach, (oversize) (Box 62, Folder 1)
- Portraits
  - Coogan, Jackie., 14 items. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Sylvia Arslan (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Childhood home - H. Hoover - West Branch, Iowa (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Hoover children (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Herbert Hoover (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Jesse Clark Hoover and Hilda Minthorn Hoover (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Mrs. Leavitt and Mary Hoover (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Mary Minthorn (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Portraits (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Shaw Dancing Schools (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - Sunday players - Bible radio (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - E.W. Blatchford (Box 50, Folder 14)
  - Yervant Kaloustian (Box 50, Folder 15)
  - A. Bartlett (Box 50, Folder 16)
  - Women (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - Comedy (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - Autographed pictures (Box 58, Folder 6)
    Including Mary Pickford and others
  - Gloria Swanson (Box 58, Folder 7)
  - Drawing of a man by William Wilke (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - Women, [2 folders.] (Box 63, Folder 5-6)
  - Men, Women, Children (Box 63, Folder 7)
  - Theodore Hoover, Herbert Hoover and Mary Hoover (Box 65, Folder 27)
  - Santa Monica - Malibu
    - Santa Monica Light Opera (Box 43, Folder 11)
- Posters
  - Poster: "Stand by us a little longer - The Golden Rule Orphans". (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Posters of Rancho Malibu La Costa., 1927 - 1928; 17 items, 47.7 cms. x 31.8 cms. (Box 11, Folder 3)
    Photographs by Adelbert Bartlett.
- Religious Paintings
  - Notes and clippings (Box 56, Folder 11)
  - [religious paintings], [3 folders.] (Box 56, Folder 12-14)
- Salon prints, mounted and signed
  - At sea - aboard the Leviathan. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - May Wreaths (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Web of life. (Box 7, Folder 6)
    (Exhibited at Los Angeles Camera Club, 1925; Los Angeles Camera Pictorialists, 1925; Pittsburgh Salon, 1926; and Chicago World's Fair, 1933.)
  - Bridge of Sighs. (Box 7, Folder 10)
    (Exhibited at the Pittsburgh Salon, 1926; Los Angeles Camera Pictorialists, 1926)
  - Afternoon of Kings (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Arch of Constantine (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Minaret, 2 copies. (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - [Adelbert Bartlett in photograph], Billboards (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Manganopegada (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - The New Day. (Box 7, Folder 32)
    (Exhibited at Los Angeles Camera Pictorialists, 1926; Pittsburgh Salon, 1927)
  - Endymion (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - The Lord is my shepherd (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - The rod and Thy staff., 2 copies. (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Tower of darkness (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Adelbert Bartlett (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Egypt
    - Nile Sunset (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Old Egypt (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Cairo (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Greece
    - Temple fires relighted (Athens) (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Parthenon (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Isle of Ulysses - Corfu (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Ancient Greece today. (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Mount Parnassus (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Villa Ariadne., [2 copies] (Box 7, Folder 34)
      (Exhibited at Southern California Camera Club, Los Angeles, 1925)
  - Iran
    - Maid of Iran (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Italy
    - Classic Rome (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Vive il Duce (Rome) (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Pompeii (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Roman gateway. (Box 7, Folder 31)
      (Exhibited at Chicago World's Fair, 1923)
    - Ristorante di Luna, Venice (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Palestine
    - Christian Street (Jerusalem). (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Sepphoris Road (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Shepherds of Galilee (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Bells of Bethlehem (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Nazareth (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Morning in Jerusalem (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Galilee (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Gleanors of Galilee (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Megiddo (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Jerusalem - Dome of the Rock (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Syria
    - Syria (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Shepherd of Sidon (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Syrian maids (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Sidon (Box 7, Folder 44)
- Scrapbooks
  - Various Near East press releases, 1922; Manila Paper scrapbook. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Including the Los Angeles Campaign.
  - Adelbert Bartlett's personal scrapbook, Black cloth covered scrapbook. (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Contains many Near East related items.
  - American Near East Relief, 1924, 1925, 1926; Manila Paper scrapbook. (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Jackie Coogan's crusade to Greece and various national and international press items by Adelbert Bartlett.
  - Near East Relief, 1923, 1924; Manila Paper scrapbook. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Pictures and stories by Adelbert Bartlett.
  - Collection of Adelbert Bartlett's photographs and articles on the Near East and California., 1925 - 1930; Black cloth covered scrapbook. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    From publications such as the San Francisco Chronicle, Los Angeles Times, etc.
  - Scrapbook of extended captions for negatives (Box 10, Folder 3)
    #102 - 962. [See boxes 24 and 25]
  - Scrapbook of extended captions for negatives (Box 10, Folder 4)
    #975 - 2483. [See boxes 25 and 27]
  - Clippings from California newspapers, 1928 - 1930; [2 folders.] (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
- Sunday Players
  - Bible Radio (Box 55, Folder 7)
- Unidentified
  - Miscellaneous (Box 40, Folder 5)
- Africa
  - African natives and missionary (Box 52, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - Algiers
    - Fountain (Box 50, Folder 8)
- Alaska
  - Bonanza Creek (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - Dawson City (Box 57, Folder 10)
  - Klondike Region (Box 57, Folder 8)
  - Lake La Barge (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - Misc. photographs (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - Photo captions (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Research clippings about Alaska, 1930s (Box 57, Folder 2)
    About Robert W. Service, Poet and Soapy Smith. No Bartlett photo credits.
  - Travel brochures, [2 folders.] (Box 57, Folder 3-4)
  - Yukon river (Box 57, Folder 9)
- Arabian Peninsula
  - Arabian Desert (Box 49, Folder 1)
- Arizona
  - Arizona (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Grand Canyon - Fred Blum, uncle of Carolyn (Bartlett) Farnham, October 1926 (Box 65, Folder 10)
- Australia
  - Melbourne (Box 22, Folder 11)
- California
  - Airplanes and pilots at Dominguez Field, 1909; 2 photographs, 20.5 cms. x 26.3 cms. (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - Amos & Andy - radio anchors (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Andreas Canyon (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Articles and photo descriptions (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - Aviation, 1909 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Banning (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Banning home (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Bear Rock (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Bernheimer - Chinese gardens (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Borrego (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - California (Box 42, Folder 12)
  - Chuckawalla Canyon (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Clippings with AB photo credit (Box 56, Folder 15)
  - Color transparencies (Box 67, Folder 8)
  - Colton (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Crater Lake (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Cultural Events, negatives (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Death Valley (Box 13, Folder 15, Box 47)
  - Desert and inland locations (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Dominguez Adobe (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Douglas (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Dr. Louis Estes and Children, 1934 (Box 65, Folder 22)
  - Eugene Plummer (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Farming (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Figures in landscape (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Fishing boat (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Fox - Lehrman Sunshine Comedies (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - Herbert Hoover for President (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Herbert Hoover - Clippings and captions (Box 65, Folder 28)
  - HS (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Huntington Library (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - Inceville (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Indian grinding stones - Malibu (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Jan Matus (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Jean Moorehead - model (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Jenny Lind (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Juanita Fox (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Laguna (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Lake Arrowhead (Box 63, Folder 10)
  - Lake Arrowhead - figures and buildings (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Lake Arrowhead - fishing (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Lake Arrowhead - horse back riding - golfing (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Lake Arrowhead - landscape - figures in landscape (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Lake Arrowhead - M[otor] boats and canoes - water skiing and swimming (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Lake Arrowhead lodge - town (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Landscape (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Landscape - miscellaneous, Negatives (Box 33)
  - Magazines with Bartlett photo credit (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - Magazines with no Bartlett photo credit (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - Malibu relics - captions and newspaper clippings (Box 65, Folder 13)
  - Mary Betteridge (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Mawby Triplets (Box 14, Folder 12, Box 65)
  - Mawby Triplets (Box 65, Folder 24)
    Clippings and article copy, not all photocredits for AB
  - Mawby Triplets, 1935; Photographs (Box 65, Folder 25)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 40, Folder 4, Box 66)
  - Miscellaneous locations (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous photographs (Box 19)
  - Mission Inn - Riverside (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Mojave Desert (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Mt. Helix - San Diego (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Mud - paint pots (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Negatives (Box 67, Folder 7)
  - Ocean Park (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Orchids (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Palm trees (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Picking dates (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Portraits (Box 15, Folder 1, Box 42)
  - Red rocks (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Redlands (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Redrock Canyon (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Ruiz adobe (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Salton Sea (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - San Bernadino (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - San Diego (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - San Diego Hotel (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - San Diego Mission (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - San Francisco, 1925 - 1938 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - San Francisco's World Fair (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - San Jose, 1890s (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - San Luis Obispo (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Sand dunes (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Santa Barbara (Box 15, Folder 14, Box 21)
  - Scenics (Box 63, Folder 15)
  - Sequoia (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Sun bathing in desert (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Tennyson D'Eyncourt (Box 65, Folder 26)
    Newspaper clippings and AB correspondence and photo of Walter Tennyson
  - Topanga Canyon. Prier House (Box 65, Folder 29)
  - Turkey and chicken farms (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Unknown (Box 42, Folder 13)
  - Various, [2 folders.] (Box 16, Folder 15-16)
  - Ventura County (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Western Valley farm (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Will Rogers celebration (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Yosemite (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Palm Springs
    - 1000 Palms (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - 29 Palms (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - 29 Palms, 1937 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Agua Caliente (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Barrel cactus (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Bungalow court (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Chamber of Commerce (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Chamber of Commerce - Palm Springs Indians (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Desert Circus (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - Desert Inn (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Desert Inn riding stables (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Desert riders - Palm Springs - Desert Inn (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - El Kantara (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - El Mirador (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Figures on horseback (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Golf course (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Homes (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Hotels and Clubs (Box 22, Folder 4)
      El Mirador, The Desert Inn, The Racquet Club
    - La Paz Guest Ranch (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - La Quinta (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Marjore Forline, H. Bedford Jones (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Mrs. Fox of Fillmore, CA (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Murray Canyon (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Palm Canyon (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Palm Drive - Palm Springs (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - Palm Spings/ Desert (Box 63, Folder 11)
    - Palm Springs, 1941 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Palm Springs, 1936-1937, winter (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Palm Springs (Box 63, Folder 13)
      Photographs by Dr. David Wharton James from CC Pierce Collection. 1898- 1903
    - Palm Springs (Box 65, Folder 3)
    - Palm Springs Field Club - riding (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Palm Springs hotels, apartments, 1936-1937 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Palm Springs night shots (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Palm Springs Rodeo (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Palm Springs street scenes (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Palm Springs Tennis Club (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Palm Springs, desert growth, 1936-1937, winter (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Palm Springs., August 1946 - May 1954; Newspaper Clippings (Box 54, Folder 12)
    - Palm Springs., Advertising brochures (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Palm Springs., Travel Magazines (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Palm Springs., Newspaper Clippings (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Palm Springs. Photographs from CC Peirce Collections (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Palms Oasis (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Portraits (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - Racquet club (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Sea line (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Smoke trees (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Tramway site (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Unknown cowboy (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Various figures on horseback, [2 folders.] (Box 18, Folder 8-9)
    - Various landscapes (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Portraits
    - Jean Bartelmeh (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Santa Monica - Malibu
    - Coast - Malibu (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Coast - Santa Monica (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Coast - Santa Monica - Malibu (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Coastal communities - Malibu, Pacific Palisades (Box 65, Folder 5)
    - Leo Carrillo (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - San Xavier Mission - Tucson (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Santa Barbara Festival - Santa Monica (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Santa Monica (Box 15, Folder 17, Box 21)
    - Santa Monica, (8 x 10) (Box 52, Folder 47)
    - Santa Monica (Box 65, Folder 7, Box 69)
    - Santa Monica - Palisades (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Santa Monica - The Miramar (Box 21, Folder 7)